You might have heard the term 'brand loyalty'.
你可能听过“品牌忠诚度”这个说法。
As we enter a 5th generation of console releases, with Sony's PS5 and Microsoft's Xbox series X due to hit our shelves this year, once more psychologists are predicting a wave of purchases based on fidelity.
随着我们进入第五代游戏机的发售期，索尼的PS5和微软的Xbox Series X今年即将上架销售，心理学家再次预测，一波基于品牌忠诚度的购买热潮即将到来。
But why do people feel compelled to stick with brands?
但为什么人们会忍不住忠于某个品牌呢？
Writer Carol M. Bopp describes brand loyalty as a positive feeling that consumers identify with a certain product or company.
作家卡罗尔·M·博普将品牌忠诚度定义为消费者对某一产品或公司产生的认同感和好感。
This also draws on the idea of brand awareness: the extent to which customers are familiar with the logo or values of a brand, goods or a service.
同时也借鉴了品牌认知度这一概念，也就是消费者对某个品牌、商品或服务的标志及价值观的熟悉程度。
Huge companies pump millions into marketing and advertising, using analytics to determine who is their ICP, or ideal customer profile.
大型企业会投入数百万资金用于市场营销和广告宣传，并借助数据分析来确定自己的理想客户画像。
It’s no surprise that the ads which pop up on social media somehow feel targeted at or tailored for you.
社交媒体上弹出的广告总能给人一种精准定位、为你量身定制的感觉，这一点也不奇怪。
This is because companies spend a lot of time and money analysing who is most likely to become loyal customers.
因为企业会花费大量时间和资金，分析哪些人群最有可能成为其忠实客户。
This extends to the supermarkets.
这种现象也延伸到了超市领域。
Many believe that the more expensive branded products are much better than the supermarkets’ own brand.
很多人认为，价格更贵的品牌商品比超市自有品牌的产品要好得多。
Money-saving experts like Martin Lewis, encourage us to give up the premium or branded products and buy the value versions.
但马丁·刘易斯等省钱专家建议我们，放弃那些高端品牌商品，转而购买平价替代款。
So, are we really brand loyal?
那么，我们真的是在忠于品牌吗？
Companies certainly want us to be.
企业当然希望如此。
But there are those who believe it's more to do with brand habit – that feeling of comfort you get from buying the same product over and over again.
但有些人认为，这更多是一种品牌习惯——也就是反复购买同一款产品带来的舒适感。
Once we’re familiar with a brand and we know that it's OK, we don't feel compelled to try anything else.
一旦我们熟悉了某个品牌，并且觉得它还不错，就不会再想去尝试其他品牌了。
So, the next time you find yourself buying your favourite brand, it might not be down to brand loyalty, but rather to habit, or even that you have been targeted by a specific company through tailored ads.
所以下次当你又在购买自己喜欢的品牌商品时，这可能并非源于品牌忠诚度，而是出于习惯，甚至可能是因为你已经成为某家公司的精准营销目标。